Kyle Sarvas

kylesarvas@gmail.com // 630.485.9336 // www.kylesarvas.carbonmade.com // www.linkedin.com/in/kylesarvas

SUMMARY:

Game Artist with over six years of experience working for both AAA and independent game studios. Gained two years of experience as a Game Designer for a gamification intrapreneurial venture within a Fortune 100 company. Currently creating game prototypes within the Unity and Unreal game engines.

EDUCATION:

Gnomon School of Visual Effects, *Hollywood*, *CA*, *2013* Specialized Training in Computer Graphics

Rhode Island School of Design (RISD), Providence, RI, 2007-2011 Bachelor of Fine Arts, Illustration

EXPERIENCE:

GameOn (A Sears Holdings Venture), Hoffman Estates, IL, 2013-2015

Game Designer/Product Manager

- GameOn's product management team recruited me to define the creative vision and game design for their patent pending gamification platform.
- Expedited the UX process by directing the user interface design and personally creating wireframes to guide UXAs.
- Created final 2D assets such as badges, medals, progress bars, buttons, logos, menus, and characters/avatars.
- Continuously improved GameOn's UX, game mechanics, and design by conducting focus groups and usability testing sessions.
- Increased site feedback metrics and overall reception by creating various marketing illustrations and training materials.

UArtsy: The Online Art School, Los Angeles, CA, 2014-2015

Master Class Instructor

- Created lesson plans, course outlines, video content, assignments, and marketing materials for online master classes.
- Enhanced working professionals' current throughput and quality of work by teaching them a set of specialized vocational skills such as lighting and rendering in Marmoset, digital sculpting in ZBrush, modeling and retopology in Maya, texture map generation in XNormal, 3D texture painting in 3DCoat, and concept creation and texture map editing in Photoshop.

Baby Bear Games, Chicago, IL, 2014

Lead Freelance Artist

- Defined the creative vision for a Sci-Fi mobile game by creating new characters, props, machinery, vehicles, and marketing
 illustrations. Responsibilities also included rigging, weighting, and animating all assets that I had created.
- Directed the level design and player experience by enhancing the existing level design and Whiteboxing out any new content.
- Increased the amount of users by 200% as a direct result of improving the visual quality and player experience.

Radar Studios, Chicago, IL, 2013

Freelance 3D Artist

- Consulted a team of Compositors, Animators, and Modelers to create high-quality 3D assets and motion graphics for clients such as McDonalds, Blue Sky Studios, Airheads, Kia, Cracker Barrel, and various high profile directors.
- Enhanced the VFX quality for clients by creating highly accurate models based on photographs, concepts, and live action footage/plates.

38 Studios, Providence, RI, 2011-2012

Character Artist

- Produced and managed the creation of a large amount of in-game assets such as Armor, Weapons, and Environment Props for a AAA MMORPG codenamed Copernicus.
- Created organized presentations of asset progression for weekly art reviews with Todd McFarlane.
- Introduced new artists to the production pipeline and demonstrated asset creation for succession planning.
- Utilized the Agile Scrum Task system for delegating tasks and maintaining a daily schedule.

SKILLS:

User Interface Design, Game Design Documentation, Level Design, BSP Blockout / Whiteboxing, Scripted Events, C#, Python, Unity, Unreal, Lighting and Rendering within Mental Ray, Look Development, ZBrush, Maya, 3D Coat, Headus UV Layout, Topo Gun, Faogen, XNormal, Marmoset Toolbag, Adobe Photoshop, 3ds Max, Nuke, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Illustrator, 3D and 2D Motion Graphics, Traditional Figure Drawing, Traditional Oil Painting, Traditional Sculpting, Character Art, Character Animation, Environment Art, and Technical Art.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION:

Played for Brown University's Rugby team, Captained RISD's Rock Climbing Club, PR spokesperson for recruiting talent into the Illustration Department, Avid gamer, Keen interest in F2P design and the future of VR gaming.